

# VOLODYMYR KYRYCHENKO

MIDDLE WEB DEVELOPER

## CONTACTS:

+380688081851



@vldmrkrchnk



vldmrkrchnk@gmail.com



vldmrkrchnk.me

## **EDUCATION:**

**Area:** «General Medicine» **Professional qualification:** Physician

2014-2020

Kharkiv National Medical University Ukraine, Kharkiv

# **ABOUT ME:**

I graduated from Kharkiv National Medical University in 2020. I studied there for six years. During this time I got interested in programming and since then this interest is getting bigger.

I have been working as a Front-End engineer in IT industry for over 3 years. My first step in this field was the successful completion of the EPAM pre-production program that lasted for 6 months. After this period I received an offer and worked there for one plus year. During working period I participated in three big project where I successfully applied modern JavaScript (ES6, ES7), React.js library, TypeScript, React-testing library, Redux, Redux Saga, CSS Preprocessors(LESS, Sass, PostCSS), MaterialUI, StyledComponent, Iodash, Bootstrap, Material UI, Redux Saga.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

#### **Web Developer**

Marketing Operating System

JUNE 2021 - Present time

Custome

**US Customer** 

A platform for marketing orchestration, data collection, omnichannel campaign activation, and optimization.

With respect to the requirements and objectives to be achieved, React.js was considered as the most appropriate front-end JavaScript library for this project development. However, forms in React are rather verbose; that is why we additionally used Formik, which is a simple and easy to use form library. Working on data tables, we applied React Table that enabled us to create a powerful datagrid experience, having total control over markups and styles.

Data exchange between front-end and back-end was provided with REST API, while Redux + ReduxSaga were used for data storage.

#### Responsibility:

- solving technical problems
- developing reusable UI components
- integrating UI components
- performing unit-testing of JS code

task estimation

### **Junior Software Engineer**

Clearance Copyright Center Epam Systems Customer FEB 2020 - MAY 2021

ustomer, Private entrepreneur

Application that helps users to sell their articles, search for already written articles, view articles' statistics.

### Responsibility:

- Developing responsive web layouts
- Implementing client side logic accordingly to MVC architecture
- Performing components integration with the back-end
- Fixing UI bugs

**Project Team Size:** 16 members

#### **Skills:**

Programming Languages/Technologies:

- Solid knowledge: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript(ES 5, 6, 7)
- React
- TypeScript
- CSS Preprocessors: LESS, Sass
- Libraries: jQuery, lodash, Bootstrap, Material UI, Styled Components, Redux, Redux Saga
- Task runners: Webpack, Vite
- React Testing Library

#### Developer Tools:

- WebStorm
- VSCode
- Postman
- Chrome Dev Tools
- Photoshop
- Figma
- Git(GitHub, GitLub, Bitbucket)

## Methodologies:

• Agile, Scrum

#### Operating Systems:

- Mac OS X
- Microsoft Windows XP/7 -11
- Ubuntu

### Languages:

- Ukrainian(native)
- Russian(native)
- English(upper-intermediate)